What a mess...
Pino?
Pino!
Why's there a bookstore here?
I'm lost...
Excuse me?
Is anyone here?
You complete my fate
The world unwinds inside of me
The halo crawls away
You refill my place
Come and save me
Believe in me and drink the wine and take my hand and fill me up
Golo presents
Come and save me
Welcome...
to City Lights Bookstore...
traveler.
Why don't you...
come this way?
meditation    in the white darkness
Let's wait a bit...
for the tea leaves to open up nicely.
Now...
traveler...
I'm lost.
Everyone who comes here says that.
The mist was so thick...
That you couldn't see one step ahead of you?
People used to say that a lot.
They also used to say that anything that happens in the darkness
stays in the darkness.
My ship should be around here somewhere.
Whatever you've been searching for
has always been right there inside your heart.
That's how things work.
Have you seen a girl-type autoreiv?
Her name is Pino, and she's about this tall-
Don't be impatient.
It's just like that tea over there.
A good steep deepens its flavor.
You can't seek everything at once.
Besides, this is a bookstore.
I'm really sorry,
but I just wanted to ask for directions.
Well, since there are so many books, I guess there must be one...
that I'd want to read at least... maybe.
Come now.
Try holding one in your hands first.
It seems he has not yet realized
that we are on a special stage.
In other words, we're inside his mind.
In order for so many books to exist like this,
readers must first create something that can be called a society.
However, in order for people to create a society,
there must be communication with words.
Indeed...
the chicken-or-egg dilemma.
Since you can't have one without the other...
it is impossible to determine that books
are a result of a strictly human endeavor.
One is tempted to believe a divine
entity bestowed books upon mankind...
though that is impossible as well.
Rousseau's On the Origin of Language?
Well then, shall we set aside the esoteric for now
and continue with a look at the past and future of this fellow
who has been controlled by a strange fate?
Why is my name on this book?
Where did he go?
How is this...
Impossible!
This is a dream?
Of course not,
Vincent Law.
This way, over here.
Who is it?
Dorothy...
I am no one.
Even if I were someone, no one could comprehend that.
Even if they could,
I couldn't communicate that to those around me.
Chief...
That's how it is...
You know that, don't you?
This is a dream.
Of course not, Vincent Law.
According to the perspective of others, I am a part of the world,
but from my perspective, as someone who
contemplates the world, I do not exist within it.
What I see is the world,
and I am merely the perspective that gives shape to the world.
I cannot be part of the world.
That is true in principle-
I am no one.
Even if I were someone,
no one could comprehend that.
Even if they could,
I couldn't communicate that to those around me.
I am not a part of this world.
That is the limitation of this world
and the boundary between my ego and the world.
I received information that an infected autoreiv had been spotted.
That's not true.
It is not "I think, therefore I am".
But... it's true.
If you would search the facility's data records...
Yes,
it is "I think, therefore you are",
though I doubt you remember.
Wait...
Then tell me!
What is that monster?
What in the world is PROXY?
The PROXY, a monster?
You're a naïve young lady.
They're called monsters and
demons and such, but that's all hogwash.
Miss Re-l!
PROXIES are...
Who you are...
They can shapeshift into anything.
They can easily make themselves vanish.
That is who you are.
They can sneak into the human mind and manipulate it at will.
That's you.
They can produce lightning and incinerate this area in an instant.
Remember.
They've called forth planets that spout flames too.
Ergo PROXY-
No!
I am...
I am Vincent Law!
Registration number 0724FGARK...
I am Vincent Law...
You are a fool.
Having lost your memories, have
you also lost the ability to see the truth?
Memories?
I have my memories!
Then who are you?
Try telling me who you are.
I...
was working in Romdeau's Control Division
after immigrating to Romdeau Dome.
And before that?
I was looking for a job in interim immigrant sectors F and G.
More importantly,
I saw Miss Re-l there for the first time.
And before that?
Before I immigrated to Romdeau,
I was in Mosk Dome.
The city had collapsed from a mysterious accident.
It was a horrifying sight.
And before that?
I was in Mosk.
And what were you doing there?
I'm trying to think back right now!
What were you doing?
I can't remember...
That is because you don't want to remember.
Come,
try answering my question.
As long as you cannot find that answer,
even if I were to give it to you, you
would not be able to understand it.
Why?
I told you, didn't I?
It's because I am you.
Look.
No...
I...
It's a dream...
Of course not, Vincent Law.
To a bookstore, books are invaluable.
The magic that words written within books possess...
What rules this world is logos...
In other words,
the mysteries of the world are shown
by words that oft say the opposite of what they truly mean.
It is a truth that transcends time.
The word bios means both "bow" and "life".
They sound disparate from each other,
but both lead to death.
People of ancient times said pretty clever things, didn't they?
Anamnesis...
That word means both "memory" and "recollection".
A memory that is recalled...
Who Vincent Law is, what he fears,
and what he resolves to do...
here, in this place...
There was destruction.
Crises befell a planet.
The sky was lost, and the sea froze.
All of nature halted the activities that constituted the circle of life,
which was essential for humans to be acknowledged.
Those who possessed the words to tell
of these matters had already left the stage,
and it appeared that the curtains had fallen on the system.
However...
since even this wasteland forms a circle,
it has not yet been able to end itself.
For,
you still live and exist.
That fact signifies
that the world also cannot exist
unless those it has given life to also exist-
that the world cannot exist as a world
unless someone acknowledges its existence.
For example...
like the stacks of books that rot without anyone to read them.
No...
I...
That world staked its survival on
plunging into a new phase yet again.
See?
You can hear the heartbeat of beginning, no?
"The heartbeat of beginning"...
Stop intervening any further.
His nerves won't last.
It seems I got to you in time.
The heartbeat...
That is the measure of time for life itself.
The size of each organism's heart is
commensurate with the size of its body,
and the corresponding heartbeat
determines the length of its life - its life expectancy.
That is the way of things.
For beings who do not follow the way,
fighting one another is utterly meaningless.
Old windbag.
You bastard...
Intervening in the core of his ego?
Is that how to treat the guardian of memories?
The guardian of memories that have
rejected everything is meaningless!
Come, remember.
Stop!
Impossible.
We changed my heartbeat ourselves.
Remember.
Keep your hand on your chest and feel it.
It's no one else's.
It's our heartbeat, yours and mine.
This speaks the world's truth.
It proves that we are the world itself.
Follow your instincts.
The answer is already there.
The white noise that reverberates within the white darkness
is a rhythm proving that you're alive-
heartbeats that will never disappear from this stage...
I've always tried to become a model citizen...
suppressing who I am, putting up a front...
I've been trying desperately...
all the time... no matter where I am.
Even if we've run out of words that should be spoken,
they will one day become pieces that will be
necessary to form connections with someone.
And the end result of it all... is this?
I am a failure, that's what.
To keep the system called life...
To keep that world together,
someone else created us.
To doubt the system is sin.
Following all the rules...
That is the prerequisite of a model citizen.
And as a result,
within your chest beats the same
rhythm, the heartbeat of beginning, as mine.
Listen.
You hear it, don't you?
I...
don't think I can ever become a model citizen.
Not even at the very end.
Vincent!
It's over...
Everything...
is over.
I am you.
You are me.
No!
I am...
I am Vincent Law!
Then look!
I am you!
I ask you...
once again...
what are you the proxy of?
I...
Miss...
Re-l?
Even though I don't remember anything...
I realized just now...
I...
am Ergo PROXY.
Remember well.
You are merely standing at the entrance to the lost truths that you should know.
Well, it's been about three minutes now.
The tea leaves have opened nicely.
Now then, please have some.
What's the matter?
Oh, well,
I got lost, and...
Everyone who comes here says that.
The mist was so thick...
"That you couldn't see one step ahead of you" is said a lot.
It's also said that anything that happens in the darkness
stays in the darkness.
My ship should be docked around here somewhere.
Whatever you've been searching for
has always been right there inside your heart.
Have you seen a child-type autoreiv?
Her name is Pino...
I can't answer every question at once.
The ship...
no, Pino.
Have you seen her?
No.
What you need to do is to accept.
If you do not, you will wander, lost in a world of darkness,
and lose sight of the most important thing.
I have accepted it long ago.
That's impressive.
Then what have you accepted?
Now, please answer.
I'm lost!
That's all!
Well done.
Then I shall show you the path you must take.
Vincent Law-
no, Ergo PROXY.
Wait!
Vince?
Vince!
I finally understand now.
I am... PROXY!
I've finally found you.
This is a dream.
Of course not, Vincent Law.
Please
could
you
stop
the
noise,
I'm
trying
to
get
some
rest
Please
could
you
stop
the
noise,
I'm
trying
to
get
some
rest
From
all
the
un
born
chic
head
From
all
the
un
born
chic
head
What's
that...?
I
may
be
para
noid,
but
not
an
droid
I
may
be
para
noid,
but
not
an
droid
What's
that...?
I
may
be
para
noid,
but
not
an
droid
I
may
be
para
noid,
but
not
an
droid
The truth we've been seeking...
All the doubts...
That man knows them all.
Tell me, Vincent Law...
meditation  when you're smiling
about everything you know.